Finding Aid for Women's Athletic Association (University of Michigan) records, 1905-1962
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Women's Athletic Association (University of Michigan) records, 1905-1962
University of Michigan. Women's Athletic Association.
6 linear feet
87263 Bimu F81 2
Records, 1905-1962, of the Women's Athletic Association of the University of Michigan. Include constitution, minutes, reports, and other materials; also record books detailing administration of Michigras and Spring Weekend, social and fund-raising activities jointly sponsored with the Michigan Union.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received from donors numbers 962 and 5252.
The record group is open without restriction.
The Women's Athletic Association ("W.A.A.") was organized in 1905 to promote the participation of women students in athletic activities and to foster a comprehensive recreational program for women at the University of Michigan. Basketball, baseball and tennis were the first sports organized. By 1908, when the W.A.A. handbook was printed, a much wider range of activities was available to women. Through the years, the association has worked to procure adequate facilities for women's sports.
The records contain the original constitution and those of 1953 and 1959, officers reports (1955-1961), executive committee record books (1905-1929), record books (1917-1960), lists of officers, and annual reports of activities. Newsletters, scrapbooks, and photograph detail the activities of the W.A.A., including those of the Michigras Committee and the Spring Weekend Committee.
Researchers interested in the Women's Athletic Association should also consult the records of the Department of Physical Education for Women, which include a history of the Women's Athletic Association.
Subjects:
Michigan Union.; University of Michigan--Sports.; University of Michigan. Michigras Committee.; University of Michigan. Spring Weekend Committee.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1901-1910.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1911-1920.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1931-1940.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1941-1950.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1951-1960.; University of Michigan. Women's Athletic Association.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visul Material:
Bell, Margaret, 1888-1969.; University of Michigan--Sports.; University of Michigan--Basketball.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Physical Education for Women.; University of Michigan--Fencing.; University of Michigan--Field Hockey.; University of Michigan--Shooting.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; University of Michigan--Swimming.; University of Michigan--Track and field.; University of Michigan--Students.; University of Michigan. Women's Athletic Association.; Dance--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Record Books
  - Executive Committee, 1905-1929, 3 volumes (Box 1)
  - General Record Books
    (contain reports, publications, scattered correspondence, and miscellanea)
    - 1917-1932, 4 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1932-1946, 6 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1946-1960, 7 volumes (Box 3)
- Records (unbound)
  - Officers' Reports, 1955-1961 (Box 4)
  - Minutes, April 1959-March 1961 (Box 4)
  - Constitutions, 1953 and 1959 (Box 4)
  - Michigras Meeting Minutes, 1946-1947 and 1960 (Box 4)
  - Lantern Night Reports, 1960-1962 (Box 4)
  - Spring Weekend, 1949, 1951-1953, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Draft article on History of W.A.A. Activities at University of Michigan (Box 4)
  - Sports Day, 1942-1955 (Box 4)
  - Sports Reports, 1960 (Box 4)
  - American Federation of Michigan College Women, 1947-1949, 1956, 1959, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Topical Files (Box 4)
    (unprocessed)
- Special Event Record Books
  - Spring Weekend, 1955 and 1957, 3 volumes (Box 4)
  - Michigras
    - 1947-1948, 2 volumes (Box 4)
    - 1950 (Box 5)
    - 1952 (Box 5)
    - 1954 (Box 5)
    - 1956 (Box 5)
    - 1958 (Box 5)
    - 1960 (Box 5)
  - Athletic Federation of College Women 13th National Convention held in Ann Arbor, 1951 (Box 5)
- Scrapbooks and Photographs
  - Scrapbooks and photographs (Box 6)